Yashovardhan Agrawal

| ■ yashovardhanagrawal@gmail.com | 💣 yashovardhan.me

| 🖸 yashovardhanagrawal

I am an experienced JavaScript Developer, an Open Source Enthusiast who mostly develops mobile applications in React Native Redux. With more than 2000 contributions on GitHub till now, I have quite an experience with development. I am also good with designing and backend implementation a bit, so I can help out in other ways if needed. My interest mostly lies in developing applications that are challenging and are non-conventional to implement. Innovative ideas motivate me furthermore.

Education

The LNM Institute of Information Technology

Jaipur, India

B. Tech in Mechatronics Engineering

August 2016 - Present

Maharshi Patanjani Vidya Mandir

Allahabad, Uttar Pradesh, India

HIGH SCHOOL & INTERMEDIATE IN SCIENCE WITH MATHS & COMPUTER SCIENCE

May 2015

Work Experience _

Google Summer of Code

coala

MENTOR

April 2018 – Present

- Mentor college students undertaking GSoC projects under open source organisation coala
- I had mentored the Meta Review/ Git Task Lists Project for Yana Agun Siswanto
- As a token for appreciation for my work, coala recommended my name for attending the GSoC Mentors' Summit in California

Google Code-in JBoss Community

MENTOR November 2017 - January 2018

- · Mentor high school students trying to learn and contribute to open source projects with the JBoss Community
- Review their set tasks within a specified time limit.
- · As a token of appreciation, I got a change to attend the Google Code-in meet-up in Google Asia-Pacific Headquarters, Singapore

coala Remote

DEVELOPER February 2018 - Present

- One of the lead developers of the organisation.
- Google Summer of Code Mentor for Meta Review/ Git Task Lists Project for Yana Agun Siswanto
- · As a token for appreciation for my work, coala recommended my name for attending the GSoC Mentors' Summit in California

Biller Jaipur, Rajasthan

April 2018 - Present

- Main developer of the User App and Waiter App for the Biller platform
- Managed the whole client side application

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

FOUNDER & MAINTAINER

Vestir Jaipur, Rajasthan, India

CO-FOUNDER & CTO Developer of the React Native based application of Vestir (http://vestir.in) September 2017 - Present

September 2017 - Present

Addy Remote

- Maintain the open source organisation Addy (https://github.com/addy-org)
- Maintain the wiki pages of Addy (http://addy.wiki)
- This app became the inspiration for Google Plus Codes that works on a similar principle

UPDATED - SEPTEMBER 2, 2018 YASHOVARDHAN AGRAWAL



GitHub Remote

CAMPUS EXPERT October 2017 – Present

- India's 2nd GitHub Campus Expert
- · Manage the LNMIIT technical community and my organisations with support from GitHub
- Review the training of the new applicants within the Campus Experts Program
- · As a reward for my for performance, I was invited over by GitHub to attend their annual conference GitHub Universe

Atal Innovation Mission, Govt. of India

Jaipur Rajasthan, India

MENTOR OF CHANGE

August 2018 - Present

GitHub Maintainers' Community

Remote

Member November 2017 - Present

Part of GitHub Maintainers' Community where maintainers of all Major Open Source Repositories collaborate.

Hackference India 2018 Bengaluru, India

Co-Founder & CTO

July 2018 – Present

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, C, C++, Java

Frameworks & Technologies: JavaScript (React Native, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, jQuery, JSON)

Python (errbot, BeautifulSoup)

REST, GraphQL, SQL, CSS (Bootstrap, SASS), HTML, etc.

Software Development Tools: npm (node package manager), **git** (GitHub, GitLab)

Firebase & Google Cloud Interface, Amazon Web Services

Continuous Integration (TravisCI, CircleCI, Codecov)
Linting (ESLint, coala), Heroku, bower, gulp, yarn, etc.

Projects

GitHub Campus Experts Mobile App

REACT NATIVE, EXPO, ESLINT, TRAVISCI

Single handedly developed the GitHub Campus Experts mobile application. This can seen as a nice implementation of react-navigation & react-native-elements libraries, along with MapView & Geocoding.

https://expo.io/@yashovardhanagrawal/GitHub-Campus-Experts

https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/gce-mobile

Indeed Jobs App

REACT NATIVE, EXPO, INDEED JOBS API, FIREBASE, REDUX, ESLINT

An implementation of Indeed Jobs API, Firebase Functions & Authentication, react-navigation, react-native-elements, MapView, and my custom component react-native-tinder-swipe-component along with Redux.

https://exp.host/@yashovardhanagrawal/indeed-jobs

https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/indeed-jobs-app

Employee Management App

REACT NATIVE, REDUX, FIREBASE, ESLINT

An app to manage employees efficiently. Made using React-Native, Redux and Firebase Authentication & Database.

https://github.com/yashovardhanagrawal/employee-management-app